<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.3//EN" "document-v13.dtd">

<document xml:lang="en">
<header>
	<title>Applications - Archiv</title>
	<abstract>Archiv of MyCoRe or MILESS based documentserver, archives, imagedatabases or library applications
	presented in the past.</abstract>
</header>

 <body>
 
    <section>
     <title>NS-Raubgut</title>
      
      <img class="float2" src="images/ns-raubgut.jpg" width="50%" alt="NS-Raubgut Screenshot"/> 
      
     <div class="marginbottom">
        Das Projekt „NS-Raubgut“ wurde an der Universitätsbibliothek Leipzig (<a
        href="http://www.ub.uni-leipzig.de/site.php?page=projekte/andere/nsraubgut"
        title="Link zur Projektseite  NS-Raubgut an der Universitätsbibliothek Leipzig">ubl</a>) vorgestellt: 
        In die MyCoRe-Anwendung werden Metadaten aus <acronym title="Citavi ist ein Literaturverwaltungsprogramm">Citavi</acronym> 
        mit Titeln aus den Beständen der Universitätsbibliothek Leipzig importiert, 
        die im Verdacht stehen in der Zeit des Nationalsozialismus unrechtmäßig erworben zu sein. Individuelle Provenienzvermerke (mit <a title="Link zu einem Datensatz des Projektes NS-Raubgut" href="http://nsraubgut.ub.uni-leipzig.de/receive/NSRaubgutInventar_nsraubgut_00002707">Abbildungen</a>) sollen darüber hinaus 
        der Vorbereitung auf eine mögliche Restitution dienen. Das Projekt wurde gefördert 
        aus dem Haushalt des Beauftragten der Bundesregierung für Kultur und Medien&thinsp;/&thinsp;Arbeitsstelle für Provenienzrecherche/-forschung. Implementiert wurde es am Universitätsrechenzentrum (<a href="http://wwwurz.uni-leipzig.de/digicollection.html" title="Link zum Universitätsrechenzentrum Leipzig">URZ</a>) und der ubl.
        (Website des Projektes: <a href="http://nsraubgut.ub.uni-leipzig.de/" 
        title="Link zur Anwendung NS-Raubgut">nsraubgut.ub.uni-leipzig.de</a>)
       </div>
    </section>
    
    <section>
     <title>Islamic Manuscripts</title>
     <p>
     Project for the cataloguing and digitising of 55 Islamic manuscripts
     </p>
     
     <img class="float" src="images/islamicmss.png" title="Screenshot Islamic Manuscripts" alt="Screenshot Islamic Manuscripts"/>
     
     <p>
     This project is sponsored by the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (German Research Foundation) for the purpose of 
     establishing a database-supported index of and digital access to Arabic, Persian and Turkish manuscripts recently 
     acquired by the Leipzig University Library. This project is part of the DFG's "Cultural Heritage" programme in the field 
     of Scientific Library Services and Information Systems (LIS)".
     </p>  
     <p> 
     The project will set up a database-supported index and provide digital access to a group of about 55 Arabic, Persian and 
     Turkish manuscripts. The Leipzig University Library purchased these manuscripts in 1995 and 1996. In this pioneer 
     project, for the first time Arabic script will be integrated into a database that will also feature German and English 
     transliteration systems. This will provide scholars of Oriental Studies worldwide with access to a hitherto unknown pool 
     of Islamic manuscripts.
     </p>
     <p>
     The variety of disciplines covered in the manuscript collection, the origins of some works from early periods of Islamic 
     scholarship, the age of the copies and their historical proximity to the respective author, as well as the elaborate 
     decoration, deserve special attention. A key place in the collection will be taken by one of the oldest known Ismaili 
     manuscripts in the world, the Kitāb al-Zīna by the Ismaili author Abū Hātim al-Rāzī (d. 322 H. / 934 AD).
     </p>
     <p>
     Duration of the project: 1.5 years. Start: August 2006. 
     </p>
     <p>
     <table>
      <tr>
       <td><b>IslamHS</b></td><td>Duration: 01.08.2006-31.01.2008</td><td><a href="http://islamicmss.dl.uni-leipzig.de/" target="_blank">http://islamicmss.dl.uni-leipzig.de/</a></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
       <td><b>Banda Aceh</b></td><td>Duration: 01.01.2008-31.12.2009</td><td><a href="http://www.manuscripts-aceh.org/" target="_blank">http://www.manuscripts-aceh.org/</a></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
       <td><b>Refaiya</b></td><td>Duration: 01.10.2008-30.09.2010</td><td><a href="http://www.refaiya.uni-leipzig.de/" target="_blank">http://www.refaiya.uni-leipzig.de/</a></td>
      </tr>
     </table>
     </p>
    </section>

    <section>
     <title>Papyri</title>
     <p>
     Die Gruppe der <b>Papyrus-Projekte</b> umfasst mittlerweile eine ganze Gruppe von DFG-geförderten Anwendungen, 
     welche zum einen die Restaurierung, Katalogisierung und Digitalisierung von Papyrus-Sammlungen zum Ziel hat. Diese
     Anwendungen werden überspannt vom <b>Papyrus-Portal</b>, welches neben den MyCoRe-Anwendungen auch solche auf
     FileMaker-Basis erschließt und Recherchierbar macht.
     </p>
     
     <p>
     <div class="float">
     <img src="images/ebers-pap.png" alt="Ebers-Papyrus" title="Ebers-Papyrus"/>
     </div>
     
     Begonnen wurde bereits 2003 mit den Sammlungen <b>Halle, Jena und Leipzig</b>. MyCoRe gestattete erstmals
     völlig neuartige Techniken wie die Vererbung oder das virtuelle Zusammenführen von Fragmenten unterschiedlicher
     Sammlungen. Innovationen aus MyCoRe flossen und fließen immer noch in die Gestaltung des Projektes ein.
     Die Entwicklung der Anwendungen wurde wesentlich von Professor Scholl und Universitätsrechenzentrum Leipzig
     konzipiert und vorangetrieben. Das Papyrus-Projekt Halle-Jena-Leipzig war die erste nicht-Dokumenten-Server 
     Anwendung von MyCoRe. Inzwischen wurde drei weitere, technisch gleiche Applikationen für Würzburg, Köln und Erlangen
     aufgesetzt. Ab 2009 ist eine Erweiterung des Halle-Jena-Leipzig Projektes um die Erfassung von
     ca. 1500 Ostraka in Arbeit.
     <br/>
     <p class="klein">P. Lips. Inv. 546 = P. Lips. I 2 (Griechisch)</p><br/>
     <br/>
     <br/>
     <br/>
     </p>
     
     <p> 
     <div class="float">
     <img src="images/papyrusportal.jpg" alt="Papyrus-Portal Logo" title="Ebers-Papyrus"/>
     </div>
        
     Einen neuen Meilenstein stellt das am 27.10.2008 eingeweihte Papyrus-Portal dar. Mit dieser Anwendung wurde
     eine gemeinsame Plattform aller bisher in Deutschland katalogisierten und digitalisierten Sammlungen geschaffen,
     über welche auch eine einheitliche Recherche möglich ist. Das Programm nutzt im Gegensatz zu allen anderen
     vor allem die MyCoRe-Funktionalitäten der Suche über entfernte Hosts. 
     </p>
     <p>
     <table>
      <tr>
       <td><b>Papyrus-Portal</b></td><td>Laufzeit: 01.11.2007-30.10.2008</td><td><a href="http://www.papyrusportal.de/" target="_blank" alt="Link zur MyCoRe-Anwendung Papyrus-Portal" title="Link zur MyCoRe-Anwendung Papyrus-Portal">http://www.papyrusportal.de/</a></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
       <td><b>Halle-Jena-Leipzig</b></td><td>Laufzeit: 01.08.2004-</td><td><a href="http://papyri-leipzig.dl.uni-leipzig.de/" target="_blank" alt="Link zur MyCoRe-Papyrus-Anwendung Halle-Jena-Leipzig" title="Link zur MyCoRePapyrus-Anwendung Halle-Jena-Leipzig">http://papyri-leipzig.dl.uni-leipzig.de/</a></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
       <td><b>Würzburg</b></td><td>Laufzeit: abgeschlossen</td><td><a href="http://papyri-wuerzburg.dl.uni-leipzig.de/" target="_blank" alt="Link zur MyCoRe-Papyrus-Anwendung Würzburg" title="Link zur MyCoRe-Papyrus-Anwendung Würzburg ">http://papyri-wuerzburg.dl.uni-leipzig.de/</a></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
       <td><b>Köln</b></td><td>Laufzeit: fortlaufend</td><td><a href="http://papyri-koeln.dl.uni-leipzig.de//" target="_blank" alt="Link zur MyCoRe-Papyrus-Anwendung Köln" title="Link zur MyCoRe-Papyrus-Anwendung Köln">http://papyri-koeln.dl.uni-leipzig.de/</a></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
       <td><b>Erlangen</b></td><td>Laufzeit: fortlaufend</td><td><a href="http://papyri-erlangen.dl.uni-leipzig.de/" target="_blank" alt="Link zur MyCoRe-Papyrus-Anwendung Erlangen" title="Link zur MyCoRe-Papyrus-Anwendung Erlangen">http://papyri-erlangen.dl.uni-leipzig.de/</a></td>
      </tr>
     </table>
     </p>
    </section>

 
    <section>
     <title>DocPortal (Demo)</title>
      
      <img class="float2" src="images/docportalscreen.png" alt="DocPortal Screenshot" title="DocPortal Screenshot"/> 
      
     <div class="marginbottom">
       DocPortal is a simple sample application of MyCoRe, which implements a publication server with typical Dublin Core 
       metadata fields and the three object types "document", "author" and "institution".
       This application is to be seen as an example and reference, by no means as a directly productively usable document 
       server. But you can use DocPortal as a source system for the development of your own application.<br/>




       <a href="http://www.mycore.de:8291/" target="_blank" title="Link to DocPortal">Live-Demo of the DocPortal sample application</a>
       </div>
    </section>

    <section>
     <title>KiBiDaNo</title>
     <p class="fett">Kieler Bilddatenbank Naher Osten</p>
     <p>
     Institut für Alttestamentliche Wissenschaft und Biblische Archäologie der Christian-Albrechts-Universität<br />
      Lehrstuhl Prof. Bartelmus
      </p>
      <p>
      URL: <a href="http://www.uni-kiel.de/kibidano/">http://www.uni-kiel.de/kibidano</a><br />
      Kontakt: <a href="mailto:kibidano@email.uni-kiel.de" style="">kibidano@email.uni-kiel.de</a> oder    
      <a href="mailto:rbartelmus@email.uni-kiel.de">rbartelmus@email.uni-kiel.de</a>
      </p>
      <p>
      KiBiDaNo ist eine vom Institut für Alttestamentliche Wissenschaft und Biblische Archäologie der 
      Christian-Albrechts-Universität zu <strong>Ki</strong>el (Lehrstuhl Prof. Bartelmus) initiierte und   
      verantwortlich betreute <strong>Bi</strong>ld<strong>da</strong>tenbank zum <strong>N</strong>ahen 
      <strong>O</strong>sten (Irak, Iran, Israel, Jordanien, Libanon, Palästina,Syrien, Türkei - später auch 
      Ägypten), deren Bilder <em>in der veröffentlichten Form</em> von jedermann privat oder in Zusammenhang 
      mit Lehrveranstaltungen <em>kostenlos</em> genutzt werden können. Der primäre Adressatenkreis ergibt 
      sich aus der letzteren Bemerkung: Für Lehrende und Lernende, die in irgendeiner Form mit dem Nahen   
      Osten zu tun haben - seien sie kulturwissenschaftlich, geographisch oder wirtschaftswissenschaftlich 
      interessiert - soll ein umfassendes Set an Bildmaterial aus dieser in ihrer Bedeutung  kaum zu 
      überschätzenden Region zur Verfügung gestellt werden. Dementsprechend enthält die Datenbank gelegentlich 
      auch mehrere ähnliche Bilder von ein- und demselben Objekt - die unterschiedlichen Versionen 
      repräsentieren unterschiedliche Sichtweisen. Vorlesungen, Seminarvorträge, Schulstunden o.ä. können mit 
      Hilfe von KiBiDaNO ohne größeren Arbeitsaufwand um eine visuelle Komponente ergänzt werden: Die 
      Datenqualität der mit dem Farbprofil Adobe RGB (1998) generierten Bilder ist so bemessen, daß die 
      ausgewählten und - in der vergrößerten Form (vgl. die Lupe unter den Bildern) - auf den eigenen Rechner 
      heruntergeladenen Objekte problemlos mit einem Datenprojektor (Beamer) in guter Qualität vorgeführt 
      werden können, sofern die Vergrößerung nicht auf eine Fläche von mehr als ca. 1,5 x 2 m erfolgt. Zum 
      Ausdruck in kommerziell vertriebenen Veröffentlichungen können alle Bilder auch in besserer Qualität   
      [jpg- oder tif-Format, ggf. gewandelt in den Arbeitsfarbraum CMYK (Euroscale Coated v2) mit einer 
      Auflösung von bis zu 4000 Pixel pro inch] gegen Bezahlung bestellt werden: Dabei erzielte Einnahmen 
      werden im Rahmen des Projekts   zur Beschaffung neuen Materials bzw. einer verbesserten Präsentation 
      genutzt - KIBIDANO ist ein Non-Profit-Projekt, das von der CAU Kiel unter erheblichem finanziellen 
      Aufwand auf den Weg gebracht wurde, das sich aber längerfristig selbst tragen soll.
      </p>
      <p>
      Die ältesten in KiBiDaNO publizierten Bilder sind Reproduktionen von Photographien vom Beginn des 20. 
      Jahrhunderts, andere stammen aus den fünfziger Jahren des selben Jahrhunderts, viele aus den sechziger 
      und siebziger Jahren, so daß KiBiDaNO nicht nur aktuelles Bildmaterial zur Verfügung stellt, sondern 
      auch historische   Bilder von Objekten, die infolge von Naturkatastrophen (Erdbeben, Überschwemmungen), 
      kriegerischen Ereignissen oder sonstigen menschlichen Eingriffen inzwischen nicht mehr existieren oder   
      aber stark verändert wurden. Nach <strong>Stand von Oktober 2007</strong> präsentiert KiBiDaNO Bilder 
      von folgenden Photographen: Afshin Bakhtiar, Alexa Bartelmus, Corinna Bartelmus, Heide Bartelmus, 
      Rüdiger Bartelmus, Bernd Bäss (†), Barbara Hertenberger, Ulrich Hübner, Jens Kamlah, Christiane 
      Krolovitsch, Jascha Lemburg, Claas Oberbeck, Taghi Rahnemai, Werner Riedel,Christian Rose, Günter 
      Schiemenz, Hans-Joachim Stoebe (†), Ina Willi-Plein - weitere Beiträger sind jederzeit willkommen. An 
      der technischen und wissenschaftlichen Bearbeitung der Bilder beteiligt waren/sind: Carsten Binder,   
      Christian Demandt, Corinna Felsch, Tom Fleischer, Sybille Kambeck, Christiane Krolovitsch, Mareike Meier, 
      Jan Marr, Tilman   Neuschild, Christian Rose, Sven Lesemann, Moya Tönnies. Wissenschaftlich beratend 
      tätig waren / sind (neben den Wissenschaftlern unter den Photographen): Silke Göttsch-Elten (Volkskunde), 
      Anja Pistor-Hatam (Islamwissenschaft), Horst Sterr (Geographie), Josef Wiesehöfer (Alte Geschichte). 
      Die technische Betreuung des Projekts liegt bei Dirk Krämer vom Rechenzentrum der CAU.
      </p>
      <img class="float" src="images/kibidano_klein.png" alt="Kibidano Screenshot" title="KiBiDaNo Screenshot"/>
      <p>
      Die Publikation der derzeit vorhandenen rund 12000 Bilder (10000 davon sind bereits in elektronischer 
      Form verfügbar, mehr als 5200 publiziert) erfolgt sukzessive und (aus arbeitstechnischen Gründen) in 
      unterschiedlichen Stufen (»nur Bild« / »vorläufig bearbeitet« / »veröffentlicht«). Schwerpunktmäßig 
      begonnen wurde mit Bildern aus dem Iran und der Ost-Türkei. Inzwischen sind auch zahlreiche Bilder aus 
      Syrien bzw. Jerusalem publiziert, dazu einige wenige aus dem Irak. Bilder aus Jordanien und dem Libanon 
      sind dagegen bisher zumeist nur im Status »nur Bild« zugänglich. Da bei einem derart breit angelegten 
      Projekt Fehler bzw. Ungenauigkeiten naturgemäß nicht zu vermeiden sind, sind alle Nutzer dringend 
      gebeten, das am Ende jeder Bildbeschreibung positionierte Feld »Kommentar« für Korrekturen bzw. 
      Verbesserungsvorschläge zu verwenden.
      </p>
      <p>
      Ein Spezifikum von KiBiDaNO stellt der Versuch dar, zu jedem Objekt neben der üblichen deutschen   
      Bezeichnung auch eine in der Landessprache zu verzeichnen, sowie nach Möglichkeit alle in Lexika, 
      wissenschaftlichen Publikationen, Reiseführern etc. verwendeten Namensformen zu sammeln: Die 
      verwendeten Zeichen sind Unicode-Zeichen, deren Darstellbarkeit von der Qualität des verwendeten 
      Browsers bzw. den auf dem Rechner installierten Schriften abhängt. (Der Browser sollte bei der 
      Zeichencodierung auf Westlich ISO-8859-1 bzw. Unicode UTF-8 eingestellt sein). Listen mit 
      Namensvarianten finden sich in der jedem publizierten Bild beigefügten   Beschreibung unter den 
      Kategorien »Objektsynonyme« bzw. »Ortslagesynonyme«. Der Nutzen dieser (bei der Suchfunktion   
      berücksichtigten) Synonymlisten erschließt sich jedem Nutzer sehr schnell - gibt es doch keine 
      universell gültigen Konventionen, nach denen arabische oder persische Namen in lateinischer Schrift 
      wiedergegeben werden, und weiß doch jeder, daß die verschiedenen Ortslagen im Verlauf der Geschichte 
      ihre Namen immer wieder gewechselt haben. Beim Suchen ist man somit nicht darauf angewiesen, eine 
      bestimmte »richtige« Namensform ins Suchfeld einzugeben: Man wird automatisch zu allen Bildern geleitet, 
      die zu einer Ortslage vorhanden sind, und kann sich über die Listen unter »Objektsynonyme« bzw. 
      »Ortslagesynonyme« kundig machen,   welche anderen Namen bzw. Schreibweisen noch vorkommen. So bietet 
      KiBiDaNO als eine Art Nebeneffekt die Möglichkeit, gegebenenfalls wissenschaftliche Recherchen in 
      Lexika oder anderen Publikationen unter Verwendung eines anderen (dem Sucher bis dahin möglicherweise 
      gar nicht geläufigen) Terminus fortzusetzen.
      </p>
      <p class="klein">(Stand: November 2007)</p>
     </section>

    <section>
     <title>LexM</title>
     
     <img class="float2" alt="LexM Screenshot" src="images/lexm_screenshot2_klein.jpg" title="LeXM Screenshot"/>
     
     <p class="fett">Biographical Dictionary of Persecuted Musicians 1933-1945</p>

     <p>
      edited since 2005 at the University of Hamburg by   <br/>

      Claudia Maurer Zenck and Peter Petersen    <br/>
      editorial assistant: Sophie Fetthauer 
     </p>
     <p>
     URL: <a href="http://www.lexm.uni-hamburg.de/">http://www.lexm.uni-hamburg.de</a><br/>
     Contact: <a href="mailto:sophie.fetthauer@uni-hamburg.de">sophie.fetthauer@uni-hamburg.de</a>
     </p>
     <p>
     The Biographical Dictionary of Persecuted Musicians 1933-1945 focusses on musicians who were persecuted in Germany 
     between 1933 and 1945 for racial, political, cultural, religious, ideological or other reasons. Theses lives, that 
     were deeply affected by discrimination, deprivation, imprisonment in ghettos and concentration camps, concealment or 
     exile will form the centre of the project. It will include professional musicians of all ages who were persecuted by 
     the NS-state and who lived, worked or were known in Germany or Austria. Every field of musical activity will be included: 
     composition, interpretation, education, scholarship and music management. Our aim is to provide a completely new 
     foundation to all research concerned with the destructive effects of musicians' persecution and expulsion as well as 
     the constructive effect of migration for the global music culture. This should give a better understanding of 20th 
     century's music history and of musical life today and, in addition, should have the benefit to rediscover musicians who 
     have been completely forgotten. Thus, the project has two aims: On the one hand we want to inform about every single 
     fate, on the other hand we want to provide an instrument for further research on persecution and exile of musicians. 
     </p>
     <p>
     The biographical dictionary contains two types of records: 1. records concerning musicians ("Personen"), 2. records 
     concerning literature and sources ("Bibliographie"). The individual entries concerning musicians will provide a 
     biography, describe his or her professional and other activities with particular reference to the history of persecution 
     and exile. A list of works, documents and literature and photos will be added to every article. One has to distinguish 
     between two types of records: freely formulated text on the one hand and lists of keywords that are formulated in 
     advance on the other hand. At the moment 2.700 personal records of musicians can be found in the biographical dictionary  - 
     about 400 detailed articles and about 2.300 short articles (December 17, 2009). In future we intend about 5.000 records of 
     musicians will be published. The bibliography contains records of literature (books, essays, newspaper-articles etc.) as 
     well as documents from archives. At the moment about 8.400 records are accessible (December 17, 2009).
     </p>
     <p>
     The Biographical Dictionary of Persecuted Musicians 1933-1945 uses the content management system 'MyCoRe' (version 2.0) 
     in connection with the database 'Exist' in a scholarly context. Academic texts about musicians are presented 
     systematically. They include the possibility of placing references (links to literature and sources as well as to 
     articles about other musicians) and using detailed search functions. 
     </p>
     <p>
     The articles about musicians are written by the editors and student assistants as well as external scholars. Editorial 
     work is done by the editors and the collaborator. Corrections of the articles and submission of articles into the 
     biographical dictionary are realised by the collaborator. The biographical dictionary is a source of information for 
     the scholarly public, namely universities, conservatories, research establishments, opera houses, concert artists' 
     agencies, publishers and record industry, as well as the public at large.
     </p>
    </section>

    <section>
     <title>MILESS</title>
     <p>
     MILESS is an institutional content repository developed at the university of Duisburg-Essen, and the <strong>"father" of 
     MyCoRe</strong>. The institutions that reused the MILESS software later built the MyCoRe community. MILESS has its own 
     software components, most part of the functionality comes from the MyCoRe kernel that is developed within the community. 
     MILESS is functionally comparable with the reference application DocPortal. MILESS can be downloaded and installed 
     separately, all MyCoRe packages are already included in the distribution (see below).
     </p>
     
     <img class="float" src="images/miless-dokument.png" alt="Screenshot MILESS document" title="Screenshot MILESS document"/>
     
     <p> 
     MILESS can be used to manage and archive electronic <strong>publications</strong> and <strong>thesis papers</strong>, 
     but also <strong>multimedia learning and teaching material</strong> like <strong>animations, simulations, audio and 
     video files</strong>. In this way, users are provided with a uniform and systematic access to scripts, foils and other 
     digital documents that are archived and permanently made available in the repository. To accomplish this, MILESS not 
     only manages descriptive metadata using the <strong>Dublin Core</strong> standard, but also stores the associated files 
     in its own internal structure, so that availability for preparation or direct use within a lecture can be guaranteed.
     </p>
     <p>
     Users can find content using various <strong>search masks</strong>, <strong>browsing</strong> the organizational 
     structure or hierarchical scientific classifications, or using a <strong>A-Z index</strong> of creator and publisher 
     names. Access to every document or single file is also possible using a direct URL or unique ID. MILESS manages any type 
     of files. All file collections can be downloaded as <strong>zip archives</strong> that automatically are created on 
     demand. Authors can ingest and edit their documents and files at every time from every place using an easy-to-use    
    <strong>web interface</strong>. 
     </p>
     
     <img class="float2" src="images/miless-semesterapparat.png" alt="Screenshot MILLESS Reserve Collection" title="Screenshot MILLESS Reserve Collection"/>
     
     <p>
     Using the module <strong>"Online Reserve Collections",</strong> instructors can provide literature lists, links, digitized 
     texts from journal articles and book chapters, as well as other files to their students. Instructors can manage their 
     contents using simple online forms, that afterwards initiate the required services like bool loan and digitization at the 
     local library. Knowledge in development of web pages is not necessary.
     </p>
     <img class="float" src="images/miless-bearbeiten.png" title="Screenshot MILESS entry form" alt="Screenshot MILESS entry form"/>
     <p>
     MILESS supports the <strong>Open Archives initiative</strong> and its metadata harvesting protocol (OAI-PMH 2.0). Using 
     the OAI data provider interface, both metadata and content of thesis papers and other publications are distributed, 
     collected by OAI service providers world-wide and become available in the scientific world. MILESS supports the national 
     OAI profiles <strong>XMetaDiss</strong> and <strong>XEpicur</strong>, which is an interface to the german national 
     library, the Deutsche Nationalbibliothek. Furthermore, a direct <strong>access for search engine robots</strong> is 
     implemented, through which content can be indexed and found by internet search engines like google. MILESS also has an 
     interface based on <strong>web services</strong> standards that can be used to search, manage and retrieve content and 
     integrate MILESS with third-party systems.
     </p>
     <p class="fett">New in version 2.1:</p>
     <ul>
     <li>
     Web Services to integrate MILESS with third party systems, for example learning management software: Creating, 
     managing, uploading and querying content using SOAP interfaces 
     </li>
     <li>
     SCORM content package archiving: Search in the metadata of e-learning packages, integrated SCORM viewer
     </li>
     <li>
     Support for persistent identifiers (URNs, urn:nbn:de) for e-publications and automated notification of Deutsche 
     Nationalbibliothek using email or OAI interfaces
     </li>
     <li>
     Workflow for realease of e-publications: self-archiving and self-publishing 
     </li>
     <li>
     Animated tutorials for authors: simply see how it can be done
     </li>
     <li>
    Individual access statistics for every document: How is your material being used?
     </li>
     <li>
     Online-WYSIWYG-HTML-editor for Reserve Collections
     </li>
     </ul>
     <p>
     MILESS runs on Sun Solaris 9 (or higher version), Microsoft Windows XP, Linux and IBM AIX 5 (or higher version). It has 
     been tested with <strong>MySQL</strong> 4.0 (or higher version), IBM DB2 8.2 (or higher version) and Oracle 8. You need 
     the freely available <strong>Java 2</strong> SDK, Standard Edition, Version 1.4.2 or higher, together with the Java 
     build tool Apache Ant (version 1.6.2 or higher). MILESS is a Java servlet application which runs in any servlet 
     container like Apache <strong>Tomcat</strong> 5.0.28 (recommended), the commercial system IBM WebSphere or other servlet 
     containers. If you run a Real server version 8, a <strong>Helix 
     Universal Server</strong> 9 (or higher version), or the IBM VideoCharger server version 7 or higher, MILESS can store 
     audio and video files on these servers and stream them from there.
     </p>
     <p>
     You can find further information on downloading and installing MILESS at  
     <a href="http://duepublico.uni-duisburg-essen.de/about/nachnutzung.xml">
     http://duepublico.uni-duisburg-essen.de/about/nachnutzung.xml</a>
     </p>
     <p>MILESS is being used at multiple german universities:</p>
     <ul>
     <li>University of Duisburg-Essen: <a href="http://duepublico.uni-duisburg-essen.de" title="DuEPublico Duisburg-Essen Publications Online" target="_blank">DuEPublico</a></li>
     <li>University of Münster: <a href="http://miami.uni-muenster.de/" title="miami münstersches informations- und archivsystem für multimediale inhalte" target="_blank">MIAMI</a></li>
     <li>University of Jena: <a href="http://www.db-thueringen.de/" title="dbt Digitale Bibliothek Thüringen" target="_blank">Digitale Bibliothek Thüringen</a></li>
     <li>University of Freiburg: <a href="http://freimore.uni-freiburg.de/" title="FreiMORE FREIburgerMultimediaObjectREpostitory" target="_blank">FreiMORE</a></li>
     <li>University of Düsseldorf: <a href="http://docserv.uni-duesseldorf.de/" title="Düsseldorfer Dokumenten- und Publikationsservice" target="_blank">Online-Semesterapparate</a></li>
     <li>University of Paderborn: <a href="http://ubdok.uni-paderborn.de/semapp/" title="Dokumenten- und Publikationsservice eSeminarapparate" target="_blank">eSeminarapparate</a></li>
     <li>University of Bochum: <a href="http://miless.rub.de/" title="BO-MILESS Multimedialer Lehr- und Lernserver" target="_blank">BO-MILESS</a></li>
     <li>University of Giessen: <a href="http://semapp.ub.uni-giessen.de/semapp/index.xml" title="Giessener Elektronische Bibliothek Lehrmaterial &amp; Publikationen" target="_blank">Giessener Elektronische Bibliothek</a></li>
     <li>University of Wuppertal: <a href="http://elpub.bib.uni-wuppertal.de" title="Hochschulschriften-Server der Bergischen Universität Wuppertal" target="_blank">Hochschulschriften-Server</a></li>
     </ul>
    </section>

    <anchor id="zs" />
    <section>
     <title>Zeitschriften-Portal</title>
     <p>
     An der Thüringer Universitäts- und Landesbibliothek (ThULB) in Jena werden innerhalb des Projektes UrMEL 
     (University Multimedia Electronic Library) <strong>Zeitschriften digital publiziert</strong>.
     </p>
     
     <img class="float2" src="images/master.gif" title="Screenshot Zeitschriften-Portal" alt="Screenshot Zeitschriften-Portal"/>
     <img class="float" src="images/zeischriften.gif" title="Screenshot Zeitschriften" alt="Screenshot Zeitschriften"/>
     
     <p>
     In dem so genannten <strong>Journals@UrMEL</strong>-Portal werden sowohl aktuelle E-Journals als auch  
     retrodigitalisierte historische Zeitschriften angeboten.
     </p>
     <p>
     URL: <a href="http://zs.thulb.uni-jena.de">http://zs.thulb.uni-jena.de</a> <br/>
     Kontakt: <a href="http://zs.thulb.uni-jena.de/content/main/contact.xml">Adressinformationen</a>
     </p>
     <p>Das Portal ist eine MyCoRe-Applikation auf der Basis von MyCoRe 2.0.</p>
     
     
     
     <p>
     Die Applikation hebt sich insofern von den herkömmlichen Anwendungen ab, als das innerhalb desselben 
     Systems, eigenständige "<strong>Virtuelle-Applikationen</strong>" über ein <strong>Cooperate-Design</strong> 
     gekoppelt werden können.
     </p>
     <p>
     Einzelne Zeitschriften erscheinen im <strong>eigenen Outfit</strong>, haben eine eigene  
     <strong>Webseitenstruktur</strong> und <strong>Rechteverwaltung</strong> sind aber technisch alle 
     Bestandteil <strong>1 Anwendung</strong>.<br/>
     Auf diese Weise ist es mit sehr geringem Aufwand möglich, <strong>Portal-ähnliche Strukturen</strong> 
     aufzubauen - neue Zeitschriften können per Mausklick in das System eingepflegt werden.
     </p>
      <br />
    </section>

    <anchor id="cpr" />
    <section>
     <title>Catalogus Professorum Rostochiensium (CPR)</title>
     <img class="float2" src="images/cpr_screenshot.png" alt="CPR Screenshot" title="CPR Screenshot"/>
     <p>
       The <b>Catalogue of Professors at Rostock University (CPR)</b> is a project of the Research Group
       for University History, the University Library and the University Archive. 
       It has been initiated with regard to the upcoming 600-years-anniversary of the University
       in 2019. The CPR aims to document all professors that have been at the university since 
       its foundation in 1419.     
     </p>
     <img src="images/cpr_logo.jpg" alt="CPR Logo" title="CPR Logo"/>

    <p>
         URL: <a href="http://cpr.uni-rostock.de" alt="Link zum Rostocker Professorenkatalog" title="Link zum Rostocker Professorenkatalog">http://cpr.uni-rostock.de</a> <br/>
         Contact: <a href="mailto:unigeschichte@uni-rostock.de"  title="E-Mailadresse">unigeschichte@uni-rostock.de</a>
    </p>
     
    <p>
       The CPR currently maintains over 2200 entries. All professors between now and 1563 have 
       already been included. Additionally, a catalogue of chancellors, a catalogue of rectors 
       and a catalogue of the professors and university lecturers of the Ingenieurhochschule 
       für Schiffahrt (IHS) in Warnemünde/Wustrow (Academy of Engineers for Seafaring) 
       have been added.
   </p>
   <p>
   	   A CPR profile generally includes the period, the field of study and the institutional 
   	   association for the corresponding professorship. Additionally, we aim to provide 
   	   biographical information, a scientific profile and other related activities 
   	   at the University of Rostock. Articles are supplemented by pictures, curriculums, 
   	   bibliographies and further documents that are relevant for the specific person. 
   	   We will also provide links to other online resources in case they are available.
	</p>
	<p>All professors currently active at the University of Rostock, as well as emeriti, 
	   have been contacted by us since 2006 and continue to provide us with their data. 
	   Newly appointed professors are being integrated continually. 
	   If we do not get a response, only short entries will be created, including basic 
	   information regarding the professorship. Currently, employees of the Research Group
	   for University History are collecting information regarding &quot;historical&quot; 
	   professorships in the period between 1419 and 1563. This period is the main focus 
	   of current research.
    </p>
	<p>
		The CPR is a MyCore application based on the JSPDocportal.
	</p>
      <br />
    </section>
</section>

</body>
</document>