<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.3//EN" "document-v13.dtd">

<document>
<header>
 <title>Prerelease</title></header>
 <abstract>MyCoRe-2.1.80 (Beta 1) der aktuelle "Release Candidate" für die Version <strong>MyCoRe 2.2</strong>.
  Das Release soll in Kürze veröffentlicht werden. Bitte melden Sie daher alle noch
  auftretenden Fehler umgehend an die Community, um ein optimales Release zu gewährleisten.</abstract>
 <body>

  <p>
  Neben dem aktuellen Release stellt das Entwickler-Team in unregelmäßigen Abständen auch Vorabversionen
  zum nächsten Release, sogenannte Prereleases, zur Verfügung. Auf diesem Wege sollen die Benutzer unseres
  Projektes die Möglichkeit haben, rasch neue Entwicklungsschritte in ihre eigenen Anwendungen integrieren
  zu können.
  </p>

  <p>
    Um den aktuellen Stand in der eigenen Anwendung oder dem aktuellen DocPortal zu verwenden, muss in der
    pom.xml (zu finden unter docportal/config) die entsprechende MyCoRe-Version auf <strong>2.1.80</strong> angepasst werden:

    <source>
  &lt;groupId>org.mycore&lt;/groupId>
  &lt;artifactId>application-model&lt;/artifactId>
  &lt;version>2.1.80&lt;/version></source>

    Anschliessend muss die Anwendung neu erstellt werden (<code>ant resolve create.jar create.scripts create.webapp</code>).
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/mycore/files/docportal/rc/docportal-2.1.80.zip/download"
      ><img src="/images/download_mcr_rc20.png" alt="Link zum SF-Download" style="float:right;" /></a>
    Alternativ steht DocPortal mit dem aktuellen <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/mycore/files/docportal/rc/docportal-2.1.80.zip/download"
    >Release-Candidate 2.1.80</a> zum Download zur Verfügung. Die dazugehörige Installationsanleitung finden Sie
   im <a href="site:chapter3_ug22">UserGuide</a>.
  </p>

  <h2>Changes in this version include</h2>
  <h3>New features</h3>
  <ul>
    <li>?XSL.Style=versions on "/receive/*" URLs displays version information</li>
    <li>added mycore-solr to add Apache SOLR support</li>
    <li>added MCRIFSCommands to operate on IFS from CLI</li>
    <li>added MCRLockServlet to lock metadata update forms</li>
    <li>added mycore-classeditor - a new classeditor that uses RESTful web services</li>
    <li>added JAX-RS support via Apache Jersey</li>
    <li>added mycore-migration21-22 component</li>
    <li>added mycore-wfc (workflow component)</li>
    <li>added MCRContent and MCRContentTransformer classes</li>
    <li>added mycore-user2 component</li>
    <li>added org.mycore.datamodel.language.* for code-independent representation for languages used in datamodels</li>
    <li>added MCRLoggingCommands to change log levels through webcli</li>
    <li>added MCRTarServlet to generate tar files</li>
    <li>added many editor forms for different mods document types</li>
    <li>added MCRPersistentServlet to circumvent mycore-swf</li>
    <li>all deleted items are stored in table MCRDELETEDITEMS</li>
    <li>added MCRExternalProcess to launch command line processes</li>
    <li>added support to generate PDF documents in image viewer.
        see: <a href="http://www.mycore.de/svn/maven/mets-printer/">http://www.mycore.de/svn/maven/mets-printer/</a></li>
    <li>Added templates for share/subscribe buttons. See share.xsl and document metadata details view in DocPortal for an example.</li>
    <li>Added basket functionality to web front end. A basket collects objects in the user's session.
        Objects can be added, removed, their order can be changed and the basket can be cleared completely.
        There can be different baskets for different purposes within the same session.</li>
    <li>added MODS datamodel support through mycore-mods</li>
  </ul>

  <h3>Fixed Bugs</h3>
  <ul>
    <li>instances of MCRSession are bound to the first IP address (see <a href="http://sourceforge.net/p/mycore/bugs/570/">#570</a>)</li>
    <li>MyCoRe is fully xlink 1.1 conform (see <a href="http://sourceforge.net/p/mycore/bugs/516/">#516</a>)</li>
  </ul>

  <h3>Changes</h3>
  <ul>
    <li>MCRLayoutService uses MCRContent and MCRXSLTransformer to pipe XML through a set of XSL templates.</li>
    <li>mycore-media: many improvements</li>
    <li>new OAI implementation</li>
    <li>mycore-mets: many improvements to mets editor</li>
    <li>mycore-iview2: many improvements</li>
    <li>update to maven 3</li>
    <li>MCRURIResolver now implements EntityResolver2</li>
    <li>added support to switch XSL-FO implementation</li>
  </ul>

  <h3>Removed</h3>
  <ul>
    <li>removed MCRFSMapperServlet</li>
    <li>removed old OAI implementation</li>
    <li>removed mycore-imaging, mycore-iview and mycore-migration20-21 component</li>
  </ul>

</body>
</document>
