<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.2//EN" "http://apache.org/forrest/dtd/document-v12.dtd">

<document>
  <header>
     <title>Quick Installation Guide</title>
  </header>
  
  <body>
  
  <section>
   <title>Introduction</title>
   <p>
   This guide describes the installation of the demo distribution of the MyCoRe sample application software DocPortal. 
   The goal is to demonstrate how the software works. After the installation you get a complete running system to work 
   off line on your own computer. The installation should be very easy for non-IT-specialists. For installing a 
   production server system we recommend to read the DocPortal documentation and the MyCoRe documentation (included in 
   the distribution or you visit <a title="" href="http://www.mycore.de/">http://www.mycore.de/</a>). 
   You can install this demo distribution under Linux (tested under SuSE 9.3) or Microsoft Windows (tested under 
   Windows XP).
   </p>
   <p>
   The software uses three system ports for the communication. Port 8291 for the web application, port 8298 for the 
   HSQLDB access and port 8299 for the file upload. To test the editor system you must use the login of a user 
   (see table). To administrate the system use the user <code>administrator</code> with <code>alleswirdgut</code>
   too.
   </p>
   
   <table>
   <tr>
   <th>User</th>
   <th>Password</th>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>author1A</td>
   <td>author1A</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>author2A</td>
   <td>author2A</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>author1B</td>
   <td>author1B</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>author2B</td>
   <td>author2B</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>editor1A</td>
   <td>editor1A</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>editor2A</td>
   <td>editor2A</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>editor1B</td>
   <td>editor1B</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>editor2B</td>
   <td>editor2B</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>reader1A</td>
   <td>reader1A</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>reader1B</td>
   <td>reader1B</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
   <td>gast</td>
   <td>none</td>
   </tr>
   </table>
   
  </section>
   
  <section>
   <title>Preconditions for MS Windows</title>
   <p>
   To install and run the demonstration you need only a current JDK (Java Developer Kit form Sun) installation 
   version 1.5.0 or higher. This software you can download from the SUN Java web pages:
   </p>
   <p class="break">
   <a href="http://java.sun.com/j2se/1.5.0/download.jsp">http://java.sun.com/j2se/1.5.0/download.jsp</a>
   </p>
   <p>
   To install it follow the instruction and/or run the downloaded <code>*.exe</code> file. Follow the installation 
   instructions dialogue. After the successful installation, set the system environment variable <code>JAVA_HOME</code> 
   with the system configuration tool. 
   </p>
   <p class="kasten">
   Start - Settings -&gt; Control Panel<br />   
   System -&gt; Advanced -&gt; Environment Variables
   </p>
   <p>
   <img src="images/start_control_panel.png"  />
   <img src="images/system_properties.png"  />
   </p>
   <p class="kasten">
    New (system variable)<br /> 
    in German: Systemsteuerung --&gt; System --&gt; Erweitert --&gt; Umgebungsvariable --&gt; 
    Neue System Variable
    </p>
   
   <p>
   <img src="images/environment_variables.png" />
   </p>
   
   <p>
   Add the entry:
   </p>
   
   <p class="kasten">
   <code>JAVA_HOME<br/></code>
   <code>C:\Programme\Java\jdk1.5.0_05\jre</code> (or the path of the Java installation)
   </p>
   
   <p>
   and press OK.
   </p>
   
   <p>
   <img src="images/java_home.png" />
   </p>
   
  </section>
  
  <section>
   <title>Preconditions for Linux</title>
   <p> 
   The default installation under Linux is planned for the user <code>mcradmin</code> with the home directory 
   <code>/home/mcradmin</code>. Add this user to your system with the <code>/bin/bash</code> UNIX shell. Install the 
   JDK package from your Linux distribution. You should install the XPDF- and OpenOffice-packages for text extracting 
   too.
   </p> 
   <p>
   Set the environment (if not automatic) for the user <code>mcradmin</code> with
   </p>
   <p class="kasten"><code>export JAVA_HOME=/usr/lib/java</code></p>  
  </section>
  
  <section>
   <title>Installation and test DocPortal</title>
   <p>
   The installation is the same for all Operation systems. It depends that you have been installed the Java Kit 
   1.5.x or higher. Download the distribution <code>docportal-installable-yyyyMMdd.jar</code> form our 
   <a href="http://www.mycore.de/content/main/download.xml">web page</a> 
   or take the distribution media like CD. <code>yyyyMMdd</code> is the date of the distribution.
   </p>
   <p>
   Start the installation with double click to the <code>*.jar</code> file or with <code>java -Xmx1024m -Xms1024m -jar 
   docportal-installable-yyyyMMdd.jar </code>.
   </p>
   
   <section>
    <title>Language selection</title>
    <p>
    At first select the language for the installation dialogue. It is not the language default for the application!
    </p>
    <p>
    <img src="images/install_language_01.png" />
    </p>   
   </section>
   
   <section>
    <title>Welcome</title>
    <p>
    Now you get a welcome window. Click next.
    </p>
    <p>
    <img src="images/install_welcome_01.png" />
    </p>    
   </section>
    
   <section>
    <title>ReadMe</title>
    <p>
    The ReadMe text show you some short information about this installation.
    </p>
    <p>
    <img src="images/install_readme_01.png" />
    </p> 
   </section>
   
   <section>
    <title>Licence</title>
    <p>As next step you must agree the licence of the software. All own software of this project is under the GNU 
    Public License.
    </p>
    <p>
    <img src="images/install_license_01.png" />
    </p> 
   </section>
   
   <section>
    <title>Select the install path</title>
    <p>
    With the next window you can select the installation path. This will be write to your installed data.
    </p>
    <p>
    <img src="images/install_path_01.png" />
    </p>
   </section>
   
   <section>
   <title>Select the packages</title>
   <div class="png">
    <img src="images/info.png" />
    </div>
    <p>
    If you agree the license you can select the packages for the installation. 
    On the first installation you must select the Preloaded Database too. 
    If you install a newer version of an distribution please save your data and do not select the <em>Preloaded Database</em> 
    package!
    </p>
    <p>
    <img src="images/install_select_01.png" />
    </p>
  </section>
  
  <section>
   <title>Installation</title>
   <p>
   If you have select the packages and click next the installation will be start. It show you the following window.
   </p>
   <p>
    <img src="images/install_install_01.png" />
    </p>
  </section>
  <section>
   <title>Finish</title>
   <p>
   The installation is finished now. Don't push the 'Generate an automatic installation script' button. 
   See the next chapter for running the system.
   </p>
   <p>
    <img src="images/install_finish_01.png" />
    </p>
  </section>
  
 </section>
 
 <section>
  <title>Run the system</title>
  <p>
  After a successfully installation you can run the system. This steps you must do each time to run the software on 
  your own computer. In the <code>bin</code> directory you can find command scripts for your operating system. 
  This can be <code>*.sh</code> for UNIX, <code>*.cmd</code> for Windows. Do the following steps:
  </p>
  <ol>
  <li>
  start the HSQLDB with <code>bin/hsqldbstart.xxx</code> and let it run
  </li>
  <li>
  start the Jetty servlet engine with <code>bin/jettystart.xxx</code> and let it run
  </li>
  <li>
  open the Web browser and enter the URL <a title="" href="http://localhost:8291/">http://localhost:8291/</a>
  </li>
  </ol>
  <p>
  For Windows user Shortcuts are installed. You can start the HSQLDB-Server and Jetty over the shortcut menu.
  </p>
 </section>
 
 <section>
  <title>Other tools</title>
  <p>
  To use the full text search for documents you should install the <a href="http://www.foolabs.com/xpdf/">XPDF</a>- and 
  <a href="http://de.openoffice.org/">OpenOffice</a>-programs on your system.
  </p>
 </section>
 
 <section>
  <title>Installing sample data</title>
  <p>
  For testing the installation DocPortal provide some sample data blocks. Available are the following packages form 
  the MyCoRe download page:
  </p>
  <table>
  <tr>
  <th>Package</th>
  <th>Description</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
  <td>defaultsamples-installable-yyyyMMdd.jar</td>
  <td>Some little data samples like images, text and so on</td>
  </tr><tr><td>audiosamples-installable-yyyyMMdd.jar</td>
  <td>Audio samples as content</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
  <td>videosamples-installable-yyyyMMdd.jar</td>
  <td>Video samples as content (large)</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
  <td>theses-installable-yyyyMMdd.jar</td>
  <td>Some theses about MyCoRe as content</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
  <td>kochbuch-yyyyMMdd.jar</td>
  <td>Teddies Kochbuch von U. Reber as content</td>
  </tr>
  </table>
  <div class="png">
   <img src="images/info.png" />
  </div>
  <p>
  The installation is the same like DocPortal. <strong>Attention!</strong> You must have run the HSQLDB and Jetty 
  server. Otherwise you can get errors. After installation the process will load the data automatically. 
  Search after install for data like 'author is Jens'.
  </p>
  <p>
  In next month we will add more sample data packages too.
  </p>
 </section>
 
 <section>
  <title>Contact</title>
  <p>
  You can contact the developers of the project under the email address 
  <a href="mailto:mycore-user@lists.sourceforge.net">mycore-user@lists.sourceforge.net</a>. 
  Before you do this would you first consult the complete documentation to find solutions of your problem! 
  </p>
  <p class="kastenFun">Have a lot of fun!</p>
  
 </section> 
 
 </body>

</document>